Eric J. Meyer

Web Developer with a strong desire to design and build tools that enrich life, improve understanding or enhance human abilities. My experience studying Neuroscience and Psychology allows me to understand and improve how people interact with technology, and each other through technology.

74 Westview Rd. Voorheesville, NY 12186 (518) 605 - 0013 meyer.ej@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Self Employed, Freelance — Web Developer

November 2015 - PRESENT

Developing aesthetic marketing sites and interactive full scale applications for clients. Using a variety of front and back end technologies including Laravel PHP and ReactJS.

Schalk Lab, NY Dept. of Health — Post Bac. Researcher

May 2014 - August 2014

Developed MATLAB scripts for electroencephalogram signal processing in brain data analysis. Designed, administered and analyzed behavioral tasks alongside recorded occipital lobe Alpha rhythm oscillations.

DSCN Lab, UMD Dept. of Psychology — Research Assistant

May 2013 - May 2014

Scheduled, screened and ran adults and children in fMRI and MEG experiments. Preprocessed and analyzed anatomical and functional brain activity data using Bash scripts and Freesurfer.

EDUCATION

Thinkful, Online — Web Development Career Mentorship

October 2015 - PRESENT

Meeting several times each week to study directly with an informed industry expert. Practicing 20–30hrs per week developing applications on both cutting edge and proven languages and technologies.

University of Maryland, College Park MD — B.S., Psychology

September 2010 - June 2014

Minored in Neuroscience, and concentrated on the biology of the brain and its chemical interactions. Conducted extracurricular research in labs to gain experience recording and analyzing large sets of brain data.

SKILLS

Mobile first and Responsive web development.

Front and back end development, with some experience across the full stack.

Comfortable learning and adopting new technologies and language.

Good interpersonal communication skills promoting compromise and collaboration.

Technologies

HTML5 & CSS3

Javascript: JQuery, ReactJS, ExpressJS, NodeJS, Flux

PHP: Laravel 5.2

MySQL